[
{
      "question":"Which of the following rulers defeated Ishanavarmana of the Maukharies dynasty?",
      "optionA":"Ishanavarmana",
      "optionB":"Grahavarmana",
      "optionC":"Sarvavarmana",
      "optionD":"Avanti Varmana",
      "correctAns":"Ishanavarmana"
   },
   {
      "question":"As per Husan Tsang the revenue of Harsha was divided into which of the following?Expenditure for KingExpenditure for scholarsExpenditure for endowment of officials and public servantsExpenditure for religious purposesSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionB":"Only 2 & 3",
      "optionC":"Only 1, 2 & 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2, 3 & 4",
      "correctAns":"1, 2, 3 & 4"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following was the chief officers of the states during Harsha’s administration?MahasamantaUparikaRajasthaniyaVishayapatiSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionB":"Only 2 & 3",
      "optionC":"Only 1, 3 & 4",
      "optionD":"1, 2, 3 & 4",
      "correctAns":"1, 2, 3 & 4"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following succeeded Dharmapala?",
      "optionA":"Devapala",
      "optionB":"Mahipala",
      "optionC":"Ramapala",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"Devapala"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following rulers was the last ruler of  Gahadavalas?",
      "optionA":"Jayachandra",
      "optionB":"Prithviraj Chauhan",
      "optionC":"Vijaychandra",
      "optionD":"Chandraveda",
      "correctAns":"Jayachandra"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following founded their rule in the northern Karnataka and the Konkan in fourth century A.D.?",
      "optionA":"Vakatakas",
      "optionB":"Ikshavakus",
      "optionC":"Kadambas",
      "optionD":"Kalabhras",
      "correctAns":"Kadambas"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following were called as evil rulers?",
      "optionA":"Kalabhras",
      "optionB":"Kadambas",
      "optionC":"Gangas",
      "optionD":"Vakatakas",
      "correctAns":"Kalabhras"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following statements are correct regarding the Varna System during the early medieval period?Varnas or social classes refused to discharge the functions assigned to them.The lower orders arrogated to themselves the status and functions of the higher orders.Their was refusal to pay taxes and render labour services.Select the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1",
      "optionB":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionC":"Only 2 & 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2 & 3",
      "correctAns":"1, 2 & 3"
   },
   {
      "question":"At which of the following places did Avantivarman built his new capital?",
      "optionA":"Avantipur",
      "optionB":"Ujjain",
      "optionC":"Srinagar",
      "optionD":"Mathura",
      "correctAns":"Avantipur"
   },
   {
      "question":"The Chola empire ruled during which of the following periods?",
      "optionA":"c. 830 – 1000 CE",
      "optionB":"c. 840 – 1100 CE",
      "optionC":"c. 850 – 1150 CE",
      "optionD":"c. 850 – 1200 CE",
      "correctAns":"c. 850 – 1200 CE"
   }
]